But by all means, if you want to just use the reactive, that's totally up to you as well.
Okay, so now that we have that, we have this other issue, right, filter text doesn't exist.
Well, that makes sense because we need to eliminate the this and just add.value, that works.
And once again, delete that.value, there we go.
So now our filter restaurant list computer property does work as expected.
And you can see here that it actually tells you that hey, this is actually a type of computed ref.
And so this is what's really nice about getting into composition API when you're working with TypeScript.
It's because you start to get a lot more specific as far as how things are being used.
Whereas in options API, it does depend on where you put it in the code and then you kind of have to like,
jigger it a little bit to work the way that you want to with options.
This feels a little bit more like natural TypeScript because, again, it's just a computer helper method.
And then you're defining a callback function inside of here.
And then you're basically defining the return here, which is the list of restaurants.
And then basically you're good to go.
All right, finally here, we now have the, for number of restaurants, we have a dependency on the computed property.
Now remember what I said, refs require you to unpack it.
So when we look at filtered restaurant list, it is a computed ref.
In other words, we actually do need to unpack this as well.
This is where dot value also needs to come into play.
And that's a little gacha that some people don't realize when they're learning about ref and reactive.
Is that because computed is using refs, it also needs to be unpacked.
So then it's saying it's not being used.
So let's go ahead and add that real quick.
So let's see, filter a restaurant list.
And then wait, that I missed type it.
I think I did.
There you go.
And then we have the number of restaurants.
Okay.
Great.
All right, that means computed has been successfully migrated.
Now we're going to go ahead and finish this up, or actually with two more steps.
Let's go ahead and move our methods in.
So methods, right, they got this special name when it came to options API,
but really all they are in JavaScript are functions.
That's, that's really all they are.
So we, I'm just going to grab all three here and use some multi cursor editing to save us a little bit of time.
And so here, let me just delete that, delete that.
Okay.
So here, one, two, three.
So we have a const of these three functions.
We will declare it like this.
And then we'll make it an arrow function.
And then already, basically, these are the functions that we're going to be calling.
Although this got deleted somehow.
And then let's go ahead and fix all this up.
So there we can delete restaurant list.valu, switch that.
Hyde form is going to refer to this.
Hyde form.
So there's no point for this.
And then once again, we can grab that.
Switch it out to dot value.
This also dot value.
Great.
And so you see here actually, this is, again, where types you can be super helpful,
is that without the dot value, if you forget to unpack it,
you can see already that it says that I don't know what I'm unpacking here.
Like there's, there's an any here for some reason.
And so that yelling at me reminds me, I need the value.
Great.
And then once again, show new form is just a rough.
So there we go.
And then we need to expose all this stuff.
So delete restaurant.
Hyde form.
And then the last one was ad restaurant.
OK.
Finally, one last bit, as we migrate this over,
is that we need the ability to call the mounted life cycle hook.
Because we're, again, I want to show that transition over.
So one of the things we've done as a convention inside a view is that we've
provided you helper methods, right?
That's what we've been doing this whole time.
Refts computed all that stuff.
So we have this thing called on basically life cycle hooks.
So on mounted, which is a life cycle hook that we can import, as you can see here,
is being imported directly from view.
This is what actually allows us to then call those life cycle hooks.
So on mounted here, and then we basically pass in the callback function that
we'll run on that specific one.
What are we going to do?
OK.
So this is where some people get tripped up, because this is where we now sort of enter the land
of composables.
If you haven't heard that term before, basically, it's a unique term to any sort of composition
API module.
So any time someone uses a function that creates like a router, any sort of function
that uses composition API, they're currently being termed as composables.
Because they're external modules that use composition API.
I don't know.
I have mixed feelings on the name, but it seems to be sticking.
So that's what it is.
And so for in this particular case, you'll notice that on mounted what we're doing here
is we're checking for the route.
And if the route has a query parameter of new, we're actually showing the new form
basically.
So it's like a hack over a rather doing direct routing.
And so how do we actually get this?
Right?
Because now there's no more global properties.
This is one of the things I think that scares people a little bit when moving from
options API to composite API is that there's a lot of guardrails that options
this gives you automatically, especially when it comes to globally inherited stuff.
And so the way this works actually is that especially with view through going forward
with all the libraries being typed correctly and we want to be composition
API friendly in addition to being options API friendly is that we have this prefix
and composable that's being used a lot inadvertently called use.
So what we can do is since we want to grab something from the route, we want to
grab something from view router.
So by scroll up here, I can import something called use route from view router.
And so if you think you have like where how would I know to use like use route,
we try to actually follow conventions of what you would expect from the global API.
So sometimes you might want router things so that will be used router, right?
If you're using this dot dollar sign router.
So use route here is what's going to basically allow you to get all the things that you
would normally get from this dot dollar sign dot route.
So if I do use route like this, this will actually then grab the route for me.
And then I can swap this out now with just route.
And then I can swap this out with dot value.
And that is everything when it comes to migrating to the composition API.
And so as we can see now, we can actually delete this part here.
And so we have this nice isolated module of JavaScript that's leveraging type script.
And then it's done in a way that can be freely organized.
And this is what composition API really does offer in comparison to options API.
Is that now when we're looking at this code, we can go, all right,
so this is managing restaurants, right?
So in the past, right, this is essentially the method section.
This was the lifecycle section.
And then we had computed here.
And then we had all our data here.
But because we're in free form composition API then, we can actually start thinking like,
you know what?
Actually, I think it makes more sense to group all like the restaurant stuff together.
So I'm going to take the restaurant here, group that with this.
Because I think this makes more sense that we established a reference.
I'm going to call this restaurant module where we had the list of data.
We filter that data and then we can even manage that data, so I can do like that.
And then number of restaurants actually is relevant, so we'll keep it there.
But then we have all this form stuff, right?
And so this stuff, we can really just say, this is the new form module.
And then we can just say, well, for now, the lifecycle hook is related to this.
If not doing anything else, different with it.
So we'll grab that and then we'll grab this two stuff to here.
And now we have, now we have stuff organized by feature rather than by their concerns or like how they're functioning.
Is there a better best practice?
No, it is entirely up to your team.
However, as you might have noticed though, because we're in vanilla JavaScript land,
this does open us up to then creating the composable.
In other words, we could export these chunks of code into individual JavaScript or TypeScript files
and then share them amongst components.
And that's where it starts to get really powerful with composition API is that reusability piece.
Because with options API, you were limited to using essentially mix-ins,
which was prone to errors as far as like naming things and then you had to worry about things overriding a certain way.
But because everything here in composition API is very declarative,
you know exactly when you're importing something from a specific file, what it's being named,
or you can rename it if it has a conflict with that specific file.
And you don't have to deal with all the assumptions that the options API can often provide for you.
Which, again, can be helpful in certain context, but in the context of reusability of code,
the mix-ins definitely became a footprint for a lot of people that we learned.